Inventory of the Luis Kutner papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Writings by Luis Kutner (Box 137)
  - "The Talmud and the Proposal for World Habeas Corpus in Historical Perspective,", 1980
- World Leadership Conference
  - Correspondence--Joan Maiman, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 137: 3)
  - Writings by Luis Kutner, "World Habeas Corpus and International Extradition,", 1964 (Box-folder 137: 4)
    Also includes papers by others
- Clippings and printed matter relating to world habeas corpus and due process of law, 1967-1982 (Box-folder 137: 5-6)
- Writings by Luis Kutner (Box 138)
  - "Legal Ecumenics"
    - Vols. I-V, undated
    - Vols. VI-X, undated (Box 139)
    - Vols. XI-XII, undated (Box 140)
  - "World Habeas Corpus and International Extradition,", 1964 (Box-folder 140: 1)
    Also includes an article by Quincy Wright
  - 1 compact sound cassette--"World Habeas Corpus,", 1983 and undated
    Includes (1) Background by Luis Kutner, undated, and (2) "Law and Controversy," 1983
- Correspondence (Box 141)
  - Ted Frosch, 1982 (Box-folder 141: 1)
  - Arthur Rubloff, 1983 (Box-folder 141: 2)
  - Miscellany, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 141: 3)
- Raoul Wallenberg, 1955-1983 (Box-folder 141: 4-7)
  Clippings and printed matter, correspondence, notes, and miscellany
- Clippings and printed matter relating to conditions of individuals in refugee camps and prisons in the Soviet Union and other countries, and the issue of diplomatic privileges under the Vienna Convention, 1965-1983 and undated (Box-folder 141: 8)
- Fundraising--Wallenberg (Box-folder 141: 9)
  (folder empty)
- Raoul Wallenberg, 1963-1983 (Box-folder 142: 1-27)
  Clippings, correspondence, notes, printed matter, and miscellany
- Sheldon Brown, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 142: 28)
  Clippings, correspondence, minutes of meeting, printed matter, and miscellany
- Jewish Right, 1983 (Box-folder 142: 29)
- Roger Baldwin, undated (Box-folder 142: 30)
- Abe Fortas, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 142: 31)
- International Platform Association, 1982 (Box-folder 142: 32)
  Clippings, printed matter, and miscellany
- Holocaust Council, 1983 (Box-folder 142: 33)
- Raoul Wallenberg, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 143: 1-38)
  Clippings, correspondence, notes, and printed matter, miscellany
- Correspondence
  - John Murphy, 1956-1983 (Box-folder 143: 39)
  - William Proxmire, 1982 (Box-folder 143: 40-41)
- Raoul Wallenberg, 1967-1983 (Box-folder 144: 1-16)
- Clippings and printed matter relating to anti-Semitism, human rights, and Soviet Jewry, 1973-1982 (Box-folder 144: 17)
- Miscellany, 1968-1981 and undated (Box-folder 144: 18-20)
- Raoul Wallenberg, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 145: 1-6)
  Clippings, printed matter, correspondence, and journal
- Clippings and printed matter relating to human rights, genocide, Helsinki Watch News, slave labor in the Soviet Union, and Soviet Jewry, 1980-1983 (Box-folder 145: 7-9)
- Raoul Wallenberg, 1961-1983 (Box-folder 146: 1-8)
- Human rights, 1974-1982 (Box-folder 146: 9)
  Article, clippings, letter, membership list, and newsletter
- Clippings and printed matter relating to anti-Stalinism, communist guerilla warfare, and activities of the World Union Centers in India, 1956-1975 (Box-folder 146: 10-11)
- Terrorism, 1970-1980 (Box-folder 147: 1-2)
- Printed matter relating to human rights, desertification, Islam, political offense, international law, and water pollution, 1963-1977 (Box-folder 147: 3-4)
- Miscellany, 1965-1972 (Box-folder 147: 5)
- Clippings and printed matter relating to anti-Semitism, international terrorism, the Soviet Union, and world peace, 1960-1980 (Box-folder 148: 1-5)
- Miscellany, 1955 and undated (Box-folder 148: 6)
- Writings by others, 1949-1982 (Box-folder 149: 1-4)
  Articles about human rights
- Speeches and writings by Luis Kutner (Box 150)
  - "World Genocide Tribunal: The Imperative for Human Freedom,", undated (Box-folder 150: 1)
  - Research materials for a speech, 1982 (Box-folder 150: 2)
- International human rights, 1981 and undated (Box-folder 150: 3)
- Nuclear energy, 1979 (Box-folder 150: 4)
  Letter, newsletter, and printed matter
- World Advocate Center, 1975-1982 (Box-folder 150: 5-6)
  Clippings, correspondence, and proposal
- Clippings and printed matter relating to genocide, crime, trade issues, the nuclear debate, and senior citizen's concerns, 1977-1982 (Box-folder 150: 7-8)
- Miscellany, 1982 and undated (Box-folder 150: 9)
- Irish freedom, 1971-1983 (Box-folder 151: 1-9)
  Clippings, correspondence, journals, notes, and printed matter
- Research materials about human rights, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 152: 1-3)
- World Union--India, 1973-1980 (Box-folder 153: 1-2)
- World Habeas Corpus symposium
  - Invitation letters, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 153: 3)
  - Miscellany, 1980 (Box-folder 154: 1)
- Clippings, 1974 (Box-folder 154: 2-3)
  Article about Luis Kutner
  - "Commission for International Due Process of Law and the International Action Commission,", undated (Box-folder 154: 4)
- "World Habeas Corpus: Ombudsman for Mankind,", 1970
- Article about Luis Kutner, 1974 (Box-folder 154: 5)
- World Habeas Corpus (Box 155)
  - Writings by Luis Kutner
    - "World Habeas Corpus: The Difference between Civilization and Tyranny,", 1968 (Box-folder 155: 1)
    - "Statute of the World Court of Public Opinion,", 1982? (Box-folder 155: 2)
  - Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 155: 3-11)
    Articles, list, and working document
  - Writings by Luis Kutner (Box-folder 156: 1)
    - "World Habeas Corpus for International Man: A Credo for International Due Process of Law,", 1959
    - "International Due Process for Prisoners of War: The Need for a Special Tribunal of World Habeas Corpus,", 1967
    - "World Habeas Corpus and the Rule of Law," 1969, and "World Habeas Corpus: Ombudsman for Mankind,", 1970
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 156: 2)
  - Clippings and printed matter, 1979-1982 and undated (Box-folder 156: 3)
  - Writings by others, 1969, 1980-1982, and undated (Box-folder 156: 4-5)
- Miscellany, 1973-1982 and undated (Box-folder 156: 6)
- Armenia (Box 157)
  - Clippings-- Armenian Mirror Spectator, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 157: 1-2)
  - Printed matter--Books, 1896, 1933, 1977 (Box-folder 157: 3-4)
  - Printed matter, 1972-1980 and undated (Box 158)
- Clippings and printed matter relating to Northern Ireland, 1971-1976 (Box-folder 159: 1-3)
- Miscellany, 1975 and undated (Box-folder 159: 4)
- Clippings and printed matter (Box 160)
  - Futurist, 1969-1980 (Box-folder 160: 1-3)
  - Miscellany, 1970-1977 (Box-folder 160: 4)
- Writings by Luis Kutner (Box 161)
  - "Due Process of Economy: Antitrust Control of Labor,", 1962 (Box-folder 161: 1)
  - Due Process of Rebellion, 1974 (Box-folder 161: 2)
- Clippings and printed matter relating to nuclear fusion and the frontiers of astrophysics, habeas corpus, human rights, the International Court of Justice, Jewish resistance to the Nazis, and miscellany, 1969-1980 (Box-folder 161: 3-4)
- Correspondence--Institute for World Order, Inc., 1978-1979 (Box-folder 162: 1)
- Writings by Luis Kutner
  - "The Case for an International Writ of Habeas Corpus: A Reply,", 1960 (Box-folder 162: 2)
  - "Habeas Proprietatem: An International Remedy for Wrongful Seizures of Property,", 1961
  - "World Habeas Corpus: A Legal Absolute for Survival,", 1962
  - "Due Process of Outer-Space Law: The International Cosmos Court: A Proposal" (with Maxwell M. Rabb), 1962
  - "World Habeas Corpus and International Extradition,", 1964
  - "World Habeas Corpus: The Difference between Civilization and Tyranny,", 1966
  - "World Habeas Corpus, Human Rights and World Community,", 1967
  - "International Due Process for Prisoners of War: The Need for a Special Tribunal of World Habeas Corpus,", 1967
  - "Due Process of War: An Ad Hoc War Crimes Tribunal--A Proposal,", 1968
  - "World Habeas Corpus and the Rule of Law,", 1969 (Box-folder 162: 3)
  - "Habeas Marinus: A Proposal in Ocean Law,", 1969
  - "Constructive Notice: A Proposal to End International Terrorism,", 1973
  - "Due Process of Foreign Policy: Proposal for Presidential Guidelines,", 1974
  - "A Legal Note on the Nixon Pardon: Equal Justice Vis-à-vis Due Process,", 1975
  - "The Control and Prevention of Transnational Pollution: A Case for World Habeas Ecologicus,", 1977
  - "The Emerging United States of Earth: World Habeas Corpus as the Ligament of Unilaw and Global Justice,", 1978
  - "Global Solar Treaty: Energy for Peace: A Proposal,", 1980
- Clippings and printed matter relating to American foreign policy, anti-Bolshevism, human rights, the Jewish community, and the Soviet challenge, 1968-1981 (Box-folder 162: 4-6)
- Article about Luis Kutner, 1961 (Box-folder 162: 7)
- Miscellany, 1956 (Box-folder 162: 8)
- Correspondence (Box 163)
  - Mario Biaggi, 1980-1983 (Box-folder 163: 1)
  - Richard A. Falk, 1978-1982 (Box-folder 163: 2)
  - Jeffrey Schulman, 1972-1979 (Box-folder 163: 3)
- World Movement for Effective National Independence and Freedom, 1965-1978 (Box-folder 163: 4-5)
  Clippings and printed matter, court documents, newsletter, and notes
- Clippings and printed matter relating to Luis Kutner's fight for justice, world peace, and his effort to make his plan of habeas corpus a reality, 1958-1981 (Box-folder 163: 6)
- Miscellany, 1958-1982 and undated (Box-folder 163: 7-8)
- Correspondence (Box 164)
  - James E. Carter, 1980 (Box-folder 164: 1)
  - Alan Cranston, 1980 (Box-folder 164: 2)
  - Anthony D'Amato, 1975-1981 (Box-folder 164: 3)
  - Freddie Buwule Kanyike, 1978 (Box-folder 164: 4)
    Includes 1 CD-Rom, undated
  - Theodore M. Hesburgh, 1977-1981 (Box-folder 164: 5)
  - International Congress of Jewish Lawyers and Jurists, 1969 (Box-folder 164: 6)
  - Myers S. McDougal, 1978-1982 (Box-folder 164: 7)
  - Tran Tam, 1976-1982 (Box-folder 164: 8)
  - Simon Wiesenthal, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 164: 9)
  - World Media Association, 1977 (Box-folder 164: 10)
  - United Nations Non-Government Organization, 1976 (Box-folder 164: 11)
  - Sofia Zahler, 1972 (Box-folder 164: 12)
- Cuba, 1982 (Box-folder 164: 13)
- Korea, 1980 (Box-folder 164: 14)
  Printed matter and 1 compact sound cassette
- Tibet, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 164: 15)
- Writings by Luis Kutner (Box-folder 164: 16)
  - "Statute of the World Court of Human Rights,", undated
  - "World Habeas Corpus: A Legal Ligament for Political Diversity,", undated
  - "Habeas Proprietatem: Due Process for International Investments--A Prior Consideration for Investments Abroad,", 1963
  - "World Habeas Corpus and International Extradition,", 1964
  - "Due Process of Family Privacy: World Civil Liberty and World Habeas Corpus,", 1967
  - "World Habeas Corpus: Ombudsman for Mankind,", 1970
  - "Politicide: The Necessity of an International Court of Criminal Justice,", 1972
- Greek World Committee for Human Rights, 1966-1977 (Box-folder 164: 17)
- World without War Council--Midwest, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 164: 18)
  Correspondence, printed matter, and miscellany
- Clippings and printed matter relating to human rights, the Israel and Palestinian Liberation Organization, and Nazism, 1975-1980 (Box-folder 164: 19-20)
- Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 164: 21)
- Scott Cohen and Charles H. Percy, 1975-1981 (Box-folder 165: 1)
  Correspondence, note, and printed matter
- Simon Bloom, 1970-1983 and undated (Box-folder 165: 2-4)
  Clippings, correspondence, notes, printed matter, and miscellany. Includes articles by Luis Kutner, "The World Genocide Tribunal: Overdue Due Process for Individual Liberty," and "The Plot to Assassinate Israel and the Autonomy of Hate"
- Commission for International Due Process of Law, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 165: 5)
  Financial records, letter, and note
- Vietnam World Committee for Human Rights, 1968-1976 (Box-folder 165: 6)
  Letter, printed matter, and miscellany
- Clippings, printed matter, and miscellany relating to the Kashmir issue, the role of the United Nations in the Palestinian crisis, and world habeas corpus, 1950-1976 (Box-folder 165: 7)
- Miscellany, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 165: 8)
- Miscellaneous correspondence, 1963-1976 (Box-folder 166: 1)
- Clippings and printed matter
  - Luis Kutner and world habeas corpus, Northern Ireland, and living will, 1961-1976 (Box-folder 166: 2-3)
  - American Jewish Ledger, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 166: 4)
- Moise Tshombe, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 166: 5-7)
- Correspondence (Box 167)
  - Ishaq David, 1978-1982 (Box-folder 167: 1)
  - I. G. Farben, 1979 (Box-folder 167: 2)
  - Hank Greenspun, 1979 (Box-folder 167: 3)
  - Gideon Hausner, 1973-1979 (Box-folder 167: 4)
  - Yakov Kandinov, Gregory Goldstein, and Lev Furman, 1978 (Box-folder 167: 5)
  - John Katulas, 1976 (Box-folder 167: 6)
- Clippings and printed matter about books, crime, Central Intelligence Agency involvements in the Black Panthers, and the political situation in Bangladesh, 1949-1975 (Box-folder 167: 7-8)
- Articles about Luis Kutner, 1967-1972 (Box-folder 167: 9)
- Articles and collected legal writings by Luis Kutner, 1972 and undated (Box-folder 167: 10)
- Argentina, 1982 (Box-folder 167: 11)
- World Fish Consumers Commission, 1972-1978 (Box-folder 167: 12)
- Liberty lobby, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 167: 13)
  Clippings, letters, and printed matter
- Miscellany, 1972-1979 (Box-folder 167: 14-15)
- Correspondence (Box 168)
  - Amnesty International, 1978-1981 (Box-folder 168: 1)
  - Association Internationale des Juristes Democrates, 1980 (Box-folder 168: 2)
  - British Institute of International and Comparative Law, 1976 (Box-folder 168: 3)
  - Help and Action--France, 1980 (Box-folder 168: 4)
    Includes clippings, letters, newsletter, and printed matter
  - International Committee for the Support of Charter 77 in Czechoslovakia, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 168: 5)
  - International Ombudsman Institute, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 168: 6)
  - David S. Ruder, 1981 (Box-folder 168: 7)
  - Linda Gail Arrigo Shih, 1980 (Box-folder 168: 8)
  - Leonard B. Sutton, 1980 (Box-folder 168: 9)
  - Tran Tam, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 168: 10)
  - O. van Luyn, 1981 (Box-folder 168: 11)
  - Miscellany, 1981 (Box-folder 168: 12)
- Industrial fuel alcohol plan, 1981 (Box-folder 168: 13-14)
- Irish freedom, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 168: 15)
- Terrorism and torture, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 168: 16-17)
- Miscellany, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 168: 18-19)
- Correspondence (Box 169)
  - Richard Pierre Claude, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 169: 1)
  - Patrick O'Malley, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 169: 2)
  - Ryoichi Sasakawa, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 169: 3)
- Guatemala, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 169: 4)
- El Salvador, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 169: 5-6)
- Captive Nations Day--Clippings, Letter, and printed matter, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 169: 7)
- Outer space migration, 1981 (Box-folder 169: 8)
- Environment, 1965-1975 (Box-folder 169: 9)
- Clippings and printed matter-- American Jewish Ledger, 1976-1981 (Box-folder 169: 10)
- Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 169: 11-12)
- Writing by Luis Kutner--Article, "Humanism: A World Federation,", undated (Box-folder 170: 1)
- Raoul Benattar, 1966-1971 (Box-folder 170: 2)
- Human rights, 1961-1974 and undated (Box-folder 170: 3-8)
  Clippings, correspondence, newsletters, printed matter, statute, and miscellany
- World habeas corpus, 1958-1982 (Box-folder 171: 1-7)
  Clippings, correspondence, newsletter, printed matter, and miscellany. Includes issues of American Jewish Ledgers
- Vietnam veterans and the use of Agent Orange, 1979-1982 (Box-folder 172: 1-10)
  Clippings and printed matter, correspondence, newsletter, and miscellany
- Vietnam veterans, 1981-1982 and undated (Box-folder 173: 1-5)
- Australia, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 173: 6)
  Clippings and reports
- Sri Lanka, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 173: 7)
  Letter and printed matter
- Correspondence
  - Jack Arbib, 1980 (Box-folder 173: 8)
  - Barbara Bristol, 1980 (Box-folder 173: 9)
  - David Carliner, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 173: 10)
  - Desmond Fernando, 1980 (Box-folder 173: 11)
  - International Bar Association, 1980 (Box-folder 173: 12)
  - Miscellany, 1982 (Box-folder 173: 13-14)
- Miscellany, 1979 and undated (Box-folder 173: 15)
- Avram Bendoly, 1977-1980 (Box-folder 174: 1)
- Stojilkjo (Stevan) Kajevic, 1968-1980 (Box-folder 174: 2)
  Articles, clippings, correspondence, court documents, newsletters, and printed matter. Includes a letter to Zbigniew Brzezinski
- Human rights, 1968-1981 (Box-folder 174: 3-4)
  Clippings, journals, notes, paper, and printed matter, miscellany
- Correspondence
  - James Koeller, 1981 (Box-folder 174: 5)
  - Mel Mermelstein, 1981 (Box-folder 174: 6)
- Clipping-- American Jewish Ledger, 1981 (Box-folder 174: 7)
- Vietnam veterans, 1972-1982 (Box-folder 175: 1-15)
- Garry Davis, 1973-1982 (Box-folder 176: 1-6)
- Correspondence (Box 177)
  - Lynne Geminder, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 177: 1)
  - Jeffrey Schulman, 1981 (Box-folder 177: 2)
  - Earl J. Thomas, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 177: 3-6)
  - Richard M. Daley, 1981 (Box-folder 177: 7)
- Legal records and related materials, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 177: 8-20)
  Relates to various cases, including Luis Kutner vs. Guerra
- Legal records and related materials, 1976-1980 (Box-folder 178: 1-18)
  Affidavit, deposition, notes, transcript, and miscellany relating to the case of Kutner vs. Philip Demassa and Guerra
- Correspondence (Box 179)
  - Charlie Mae Brown, 1984 (Box-folder 179: 1)
  - Joan Hamilton, 1984 (Box-folder 179: 2)
  - Selma R. Diering, 1984 (Box-folder 179: 3)
  - Rudolph S. Diblik, 1984 (Box-folder 179: 4)
  - Joseph C. Fenech, 1977-1992 (Box-folder 179: 5)
  - Ross Harano, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 179: 6)
  - Steven Kumble, 1984 (Box-folder 179: 7)
  - Irv Kupcinet, 1984 (Box-folder 179: 8)
  - Robert Moosbrugger, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 179: 9)
  - Trans Atlantic Resource Corporation, 1984 (Box-folder 179: 10)
  - Swiss-American Chamber of Commerce, 1984 (Box-folder 179: 11)
- Clippings relating to Gorbachev and his plans for the Soviet Union, 1985 (Box-folder 179: 12)
- Serbia, 1979-1985 (Box-folder 179: 14-18)
- Miscellany, 1980-1984 (Box-folder 179: 19-20)
- Luis Kutner vs. Philip Demassa and Guerra, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 180: 1-9)
  Includes correspondence with James J. Grogan, Sidney Karasil, and Earl J. Thomas
- National Lawyers Guild, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 180: 10-11)
  Brochure, clippings, legal documents, and printed matter. Includes a letter to Ronald Reagan from Roland Pritikin
- El Salvador, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 180: 12-13)
  Clippings, correspondence, and miscellany
- Writings by Luis Kutner (Box 181)
  - "The Victimless Crime: The Criminal as Victim,", undated (Box-folder 181: 1)
  - "Are We Witness to the Fall of the United States?", undated (Box-folder 181: 2)
  - "The New Panama Canal Treaties: A Potential Diplomatic Pearl Harbor,", undated (Box-folder 181: 3)
  - "The Use of the Nuremberg Tribunals as a Precedent for Bangladesh War Crime Trials,", undated (Box-folder 181: 4)
  - "The Magna Carta: The Ignored Legacy of Anti-Semitism,", undated (Box-folder 181: 5)
  - "American Nazi Rockwell and the Jews of Chicago,", undated (Box-folder 181: 6)
  - "Psychiatry and International Law,", undated (Box-folder 181: 7)
  - "Discord in the Congressional Record: Toward an Honest Legislative History of House and Senate Proceedings,", undated (Box-folder 181: 8)
  - "International Terrorism: The Inversion of Relegated Responsibility,", undated (Box-folder 181: 9)
  - "Due Process of Historic Preservation Zoning: Illusion of Constitutionality?", undated (Box-folder 181: 10)
  - "Reforming the Vice-Presidential Nominee Selection Process,", undated (Box-folder 181: 11)
  - "Thomas Jefferson--An Anarchist,", undated (Box-folder 181: 12)
  - "Soviet Jewry and World Habeas Corpus,", undated (Box-folder 181: 13)
  - "Adversaries of Due Process: A Legal Mosaic,", undated (Box-folder 181: 14)
- Inventory of law journal articles, undated (Box-folder 181: 15)
- Writings by Luis Kutner (Box 182)
  - "World Habeas Corpus: The Civil Remedy for Humanitarian Intervention,", undated (Box-folder 182: 1)
  - "World Habeas Corpus and the Protection of Jews in Arab Countries,", undated (Box-folder 182: 2)
  - "The Victimless Crime: The Criminal as Victim,", undated (Box-folder 182: 3)
  - "Treatment of an Issue by a Committee of Congress,", undated (Box-folder 182: 4)
  - "Engel and Schempp: National and Sub-National Reaction,", undated (Box-folder 182: 5)
  - "Mankind vs. Mankind: The Need for a United World, Unilaw and World Habeas Corpus,", undated (Box-folder 182: 6)
  - "Cold War Espionage,", undated (Box-folder 182: 7)
  - "Presidential Power: A Profile for Dictatorship,", undated (Box-folder 182: 8)
  - "Our Extra Constitutional Census,", undated (Box-folder 182: 9)
  - "International Law as an Instrument of National Policy,", undated (Box-folder 182: 10)
  - "Charter of the Forest: Forgotten Companion of the Magna Carta,", undated (Box-folder 182: 11)
  - "Presidential Executive Orders--Government by Fiat or Operational Necessity: An Expanding Definition,", undated (Box-folder 182: 12)
  - "The Legocide of Pope Innocent III,", undated (Box-folder 182: 13)
  - "Habeas Corpus in International Law,", undated (Box-folder 182: 14)
  - "Sub-Saharan Africa: The Need for an Adult Foreign Policy,", undated (Box-folder 182: 15)
  - "World Genocide Tribunal: The Imperative for Human Freedom,", undated (Box-folder 182: 16)
  - "A World Genocide Tribunal--Rampart for Future Genocide: Proposal for Planetary Preventive Measures Supplementing a Genocide Early Warning System,", undated (Box-folder 182: 17)
  - "The Controversial Question of Amnesty,", undated (Box-folder 182: 18)
  - "The Living Will: Epitome of Human Dignity,", undated (Box-folder 182: 19)
  - "Establishing a Convention of World Habeas Corpus and Regional Courts of World Habeas Corpus," speech, section meeting, American Bar Association, Miami Beach, Florida, 1959 (Box-folder 182: 20)
  - "Geoffrey Chaucer, Law Giver,", undated (Box-folder 183: 1)
  - "A Comparison of Emergency Powers of Various World Governments,", undated (Box-folder 183: 2)
  - "The Genocide of the Gerontocracy: The Legal Dilemma of the Aged,", undated (Box-folder 183: 3)
  - "Confirmatio Cartarum: The Forgotten Magna Carta,", undated (Box-folder 183: 4)
  - "Self-Determination and World Habeas Corpus,", undated (Box-folder 183: 5)
  - "The Arctic Ocean: A Contest of Sovereignty,", undated (Box-folder 183: 6)
  - "A Unicameral Congress: Proposal for Reorganization,", undated (Box-folder 183: 7)
  - "Global Solar Treaty: Energy for Peace," a proposal, undated (Box-folder 183: 8)
  - "Willkie at Philadelphia: The Farce of Presidential Nominating Conventions,", undated (Box-folder 183: 9)
  - "The Yom Kippur War: The Homefront,", 1973 October 6 (Box-folder 183: 10)
  - "The Great Betrayal: The Defeat of Charitable Trusts,", undated (Box-folder 183: 11)
  - "The Long Show of the Dreyfus Case: Legalistics of Anti-Semitism,", undated (Box-folder 183: 12)
  - "World Man and World Habeas Corpus,", undated (Box-folder 183: 13)
  - "Legal Profiles of Socrates, Milton, Dickens 8 Galsworthy,", undated (Box-folder 183: 14)
  - "Abraham Lincoln--Almost Impeached,", undated (Box-folder 183: 15)
  - "Cannibalism: A Legal Lacuna,", undated (Box-folder 183: 16)
  - "A Preponderance of Perjury: The Continuing Farce of the Expert Witness,", undated (Box-folder 183: 17)
  - "The Corruption of Wealth: Views of Aristotle, Plato, and St. Thomas Aquinas,", undated (Box-folder 183: 18)
  - "Due Process of Economy: Anti-Trust Control of Agriculture Cooperatives,", undated (Box-folder 183: 19)
  - "Witness Immunity: Abuses, Uses 8 Myths,", undated (Box-folder 183: 20)
  - "Compelled Testimony: Immunity Charade for Perjury,", undated (Box-folder 183: 21)
  - "Christmas as a Legal Holiday: In Violation of the 1st Amendment,", undated (Box-folder 184: 1)
  - "Lincoln the Lawyer: Myth and Reality,", undated (Box-folder 184: 2)
  - "Timocracy: The Inalienable Right to Self Respect,", undated (Box-folder 184: 3)